

MUHAMMAD FAHAD QURESHI

Profile

Accounts Professional having 16 years experience with Manufacturing corporate Sector. A decisive goal oriented and foresighted individual positive and assertive attitude towards work; with a flair for multiple task

Professional Carrer History

September 2014----to date Al Raza Printers (printing & packages)

December 2007 ---- Aug 2014 Skyways Manufacturers (Pvt.) Limited (auto parts manufacturers & metal works)

September 2003 ---- November 2007 Teamwork Packages (Pvt.) Limited (printing & packages)

July 2001 ----- August 2002 Care Marketing Services (pharmaceutical Franchiser)

Feb 1998 ---- June 2001 Cibex Pharmaceutical (Pvt.) Limited (pharmaceutical Manufacturer)

Employment History

with Al Raza Printers (Sep. 2014 to date)

Resently working at Al Raza as Manager Accounts. At Al Raza Accounting Systems operate on

Oracle base Accounts software, as Manager Accounts responsible for manage Payable, Receivable, Taxation, Payroll & labor related functions with reporting to Director. My exposure and areas of responsibilities include:

Responsibilities

Individually manage day to day accounting functions and ensures compliance of standard policy procedures manual.

Manage of all Tax matters relating to Sales Tax, W/H tax, Staff & Vendor's Income Tax on FBR portal

Manage Payable Accounts. (vendor's bills checking, monthly vendor's payment Schedule, correspondence)

Manage Receivable Accounts. (customer's Invoicing, monthly receivable Schedule and recovery, correspondence)

Manage General ledger, Fixed Assets Schedule, Trial Balance and balance sheets.

Responsible Staff Payroll and overtime.

Bank Reconciliation. (Bank Al Habib, NBP, Mcb)

Preparation of monthly, quarterly and annual reports and cash flows.

Co-ordinate with labour consultants in relation to any query.

Direct reporting to director.

Individually Handle and decision maker to all matters of Accounts and finance depart.

Leadership & Team Building Skills.

with Skyways Manufacturers (Dec, 2007 to Aug, 2014)

During my job tenure at Skyways as **Manager Accounts**, At Skyways Accounting Systems operate on ERP, as Manager Accounts responsible for manage Payable, Receivable, Taxation, Payroll & labor related functions with reporting to General Manager Finance & Accounts. My exposure and areas of responsibilities include:

Responsibilities

Supervising day to day accounting funtions and ensures compliance of standard policy procedures manual. Manage and E-filling of all Tax matters relating to Sales Tax, Federal Excise Duty, Staff & Vendor's Income Tax on FBR portal.

Manage Payable Accounts. (vendor's bills checking, monthly vendor's payment Schedule, correspondence)

Manage Receivable Accounts. (customer's Invoicing, monthly receivable Schedule and recovery, correspondence) Bank Reconciliation. (Bank Al Habib, NBP, Mcb)

Preparation of monthly, quarterly and annual reports and cash flows.

Preparation of budget and forecast.

Coordinate with chartered accountant firm during annual audit process.

Honors & Awards with in Skyways

I achieved The Best Performance Award 2011-2012 from Skyways Manufacturers Pvt Ltd.

With Team Work Packages (Sep. 2002 to Nov. 2007)

During my association with Team work Packages as **Accountant** manage Sales Tax, Payroll, Vendor's and Customer's correspondence, through which I have obtained a significant knowledge and expertise to manage the Accounts functions of any organization. Major exposure during association include:

Responsibilities

Manage of computerized Sales Tax record, filing of monthly and annually sales tax return.

Manage Payable Accounts. (vendor's bills checking, monthly vendor's payment Schedule, correspondence)

Manage Receivable Accounts. (customer's Invoicing, monthly receivable Schedule and recovery, correspondence)

Prepare of Payroll and Overtime (Over Hundred staff & factory workers)

Manage of computerized vendor's income tax record, filing of monthly basis.

Handle Petty cash Account.

Maintain of selling, administrative & general expenses as per their schedule.

Capability of handle all routine works of Finance & Accounts Dept.

Run Computerized General Ledger software in visual Basic and Peach Tree.

All function matters discuss & reporting direct to Gm Finance and Director.

With Care Marketing Services (July 2001- Aug 2002)

During my job with Care Marketing as Asst. Accountant;

Responsibilities

Bank Reconcilations (Bank Al Habib, Bank Al Falah)

Handle Petty cash Account.

Staff Payroll and Overtime.

Manage Countrywide dispatches record & make manually invoices.

Daily routine work of Accounts department.

With Cibex Pharmaceutical (Feb, 1998 to June 2001)

During my Job with Cibex as Asst. Inventory officer;

Responsibilities

My key responsibilities includes focused on Inventory Management of over hundreds products commercial, physician sample and medical literature within on-site warehouses. Also liaison with Operations, Sales & Marketing team by providing accurate details of on-hand inventory, inventory in transit, and forecast with budgeted sales projections.

Responsible Countrywide dispatches record & make manually invoices.

Run Computerized Inventory Software.

Handle Petty cash Account.

Education & Qualifications:

• 1997 Govt. Jinnah College Nazimabad Karachi

Intermediate (Pre-Engineering)

• 2002 Karachi University

Graduation in B.com

Computer Proficiency:

Six month certificate course M/s Office (Word, Excel, Power Point, Internet, Software Installation).(year 2000) One year Diploma in Information Technology From "Skill Development Council". (year 2002)

one year Deproma in Information Technology From Smil Development Counter 1, 1961 20

Peachtree Accounting Software, FoxPro GL & Inventory Software. (year 2004, 2005)

ER Manager (ERP module based GL & Inventory Software). (2007 to 2016)

Team lead/Management and Solution analysis.

Others Activities

Table Tennis, Cricket & Chess

Attended various seminars and workshops on the corporate subjects Etc.

Personal Information

F/Name: Muhammad Saeed Qurashi (late)
Marital Status: Married blessed with Two Daughters

Date of Birth: 5th April 1979

Address: Block 19, Gulistane Jauher, Karachi

Domicile: Karachi, Sindh

 Contact:
 Cell (92 0300) 2543328

 Email:
 fahad.sky@hotmail.com,

References

These will be furnished on demand.